whimsical.com 2019-12-03

# Privacy Policy | Whimsical

_Updated June 12, 2019_

Your privacy is critically important to us. At Whimsical, we have a few fundamental principles:

  * We are thoughtful about the personal information we ask you to provide and the personal information that we collect about you through the operation of our services.
  * We store personal information for only as long as we have a reason to keep it.
  * We aim to make it as simple as possible for you to control what information is shared publicly, kept private, and permanently deleted.
  * We help protect you from overreaching government demands for your personal information.
  * We aim for full transparency on how we gather, use, and share your personal information.

Below is our Privacy Policy, which incorporates and clarifies these principles.

## Who We Are and What This Policy Covers

Hey there! We are the folks behind Whimsical, a service designed to allow anyone to collaborate on ideas visually.

This Privacy Policy applies to information that we collect about you when you use our website (whimsical.com).

Throughout this Privacy Policy we’ll refer to our website as “Services.” Below we explain how we collect, use, and share information about you, along with the choices that you have with respect to that information.

## Information We Collect

We only collect information about you if we have a reason to do so–for example, to provide our Services, to communicate with you, or to make our Services better. We collect information in three ways: if and when you provide information to us, automatically through operating our Services, and from outside sources. Let’s go over the information that we collect.

### Information You Provide to Us

It’s probably no surprise that we collect information that you provide to us. The amount and type of information depends on the context and how we use the information. Here are some examples:

  * **Basic Account Information:** We ask for basic information from you in order to set up your account. For example, we require individuals who sign up for a whimsical.com account to provide a name and email address–and that’s it.
  * **Transaction and Billing Information:** If you buy a subscription to a whimsical.com plan from us, you will provide additional personal and payment information that is required to process the transaction and your payment, such as your name, credit card information, and contact information.
  * **Communications With Us :** You may also provide us information when you respond to surveys or communicate with us about a support question.

### Information We Collect Automatically

We also collect some information automatically:

  * **Log Information:** Like most online service providers, we collect information that web browsers, mobile devices, and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, IP address, unique device identifiers, language preference, referring site, the date and time of access, operating system, and mobile network information. We collect log information when you use our Services.
  * **Usage Information:** We collect information about your usage of our Services. For example, we collect information about the actions that workspace administrators and users perform on a workspace whimsical.com service–in other words, who did what, when and to what thing in a workspace. We also collect information about what happens when you use our Services (e.g., page views) along with information about your device (e.g., screen size, name of cellular network, and mobile device manufacturer). We use this information to, for example, provide our Services to you, as well as get insights on how people use our Services, so we can make our Services better.
  * **Location Information:** We may determine the approximate location of your device from your IP address. We collect and use this information to, for example, calculate how many people visit our Services from certain geographic regions.
  * **Information from Cookies & Other Technologies:** A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor’s computer, and that the visitor’s browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. Pixel tags (also called web beacons) are small blocks of code placed on websites and emails. Whimsical uses cookies and other technologies like pixel tags to help us identify and track visitors, usage, and access preferences for our Services, as well as track and understand email campaign effectiveness.

### Information We Collect from Other Sources

We may also get information about you from other sources. For example, if you create or log into your whimsical.com account through another service (like Google), we will receive information from that service (such as your basic profile information) via the authorization procedures used by that service.

## How And Why We Use Information

### Purposes for Using Information

We use information about you as mentioned above and for the purposes listed below:

  * To provide our Services–for example, to set up and maintain your account, host your workspace, or charge you for any of our paid Services;
  * To further develop and improve our Services–for example by adding new features that we think our users will enjoy or will help them to create and manage their websites more efficiently;
  * To monitor and analyze trends and better understand how users interact with our Services, which helps us improve our Services and make them easier to use;
  * To measure, gauge, and improve the effectiveness of our advertising, and better understand user retention and attrition–for example, we may analyze how many individuals purchased a plan after receiving a marketing message or the features used by those who continue to use our Services after a certain length of time;
  * To monitor and prevent any problems with our Services, protect the security of our Services, detect and prevent fraudulent transactions and other illegal activities, fight spam, and protect the rights and property of Whimsical and others, which may result in us declining a transaction or the use of our Services;
  * To communicate with you, for example through an email, about offers and promotions offered by Whimsical and others we think will be of interest to you, solicit your feedback, or keep you up to date on Whimsical and our products; and
  * To personalize your experience using our Services and target our marketing messages to groups of our users (for example, those who have a particular plan with us or have been our user for a certain length of time).

### Legal Bases for Collecting and Using Information

A note here for those in the European Union about our legal grounds for processing information about you under EU data protection laws, which is that our use of your information is based on the grounds that: (1) The use is necessary in order to fulfill our commitments to you under our Terms of Service or other agreements with you or is necessary to administer your account–for example, in order to enable access to our website on your device or charge you for a paid plan; or (2) The use is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation; or (3) The use is necessary in order to protect your vital interests or those of another person; or (4) We have a legitimate interest in using your information–for example, to provide and update our Services, to improve our Services so that we can offer you an even better user experience, to safeguard our Services, to communicate with you, to measure, gauge, and improve the effectiveness of our advertising, and better understand user retention and attrition, to monitor and prevent any problems with our Services, and to personalize your experience; or (5) You have given us your consent–for example before we place certain cookies on your device and access and analyze them later on.

## Sharing Information

We do not sell our users’ private personal information. We share information about you in the limited circumstances spelled out below and with appropriate safeguards on your privacy:

  * **Subsidiaries, Employees, and Independent Contractors:** We may disclose information about you to our subsidiaries, our employees, and individuals who are our independent contractors that need to know the information in order to help us provide our Services or to process the information on our behalf. We require our subsidiaries, employees, and independent contractors to follow this Privacy Policy for personal information that we share with them.
  * **Third Party Vendors:** We may share information about you with third party vendors who need to know information about you in order to provide their services to us, or to provide their services to you or your site. This group includes vendors that help us provide our Services to you (like payment providers that process your credit and debit card information), those that assist us with our marketing efforts (e.g. by providing tools for identifying a specific marketing target group or improving our marketing campaigns), those that help us understand and enhance our Services (like analytics providers). We require vendors to agree to privacy commitments in order to share information with them.
  * **Legal Requests:** We may disclose information about you in response to a subpoena, court order, or other governmental request, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.
  * **To Protect Rights, Property, and Others:** We may disclose information about you when we believe in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the property or rights of Whimsical, third parties, or the public at large. For example, if we have a good faith belief that there is an imminent danger of death or serious physical injury, we may disclose information related to the emergency without delay.
  * **Business Transfers:** In connection with any merger, sale of company assets, or acquisition of all or a portion of our business by another company, or in the unlikely event that Whimsical goes out of business or enters bankruptcy, user information would likely be one of the assets that is transferred or acquired by a third party. If any of these events were to happen, this Privacy Policy would continue to apply to your information and the party receiving your information may continue to use your information, but only consistent with this Privacy Policy.
  * **With Your Consent:** We may share and disclose information with your consent or at your direction. For example, we may share your information with third parties with which you authorize us to do so.
  * **Aggregated or De-Identified Information:** We may share information that has been aggregated or reasonably de-identified, so that the information could not reasonably be used to identify you. For instance, we may publish aggregate statistics about the use of our Services.
  * **Published Support Requests:** And if you send us a request (for example, via a support email or one of our feedback mechanisms), we reserve the right to publish that request in order to help us clarify or respond to your request or to help us support other users.

## How Long We Keep Information

We generally discard information about you when we no longer need the information for the purposes for which we collect and use it–which are described in the section above on How and Why We Use Information–and we are not legally required to continue to keep it. For example, we keep the web server logs that record information about a visitor to one of Whimsical’s website, such as the visitor’s IP address, browser type, and operating system, for approximately 30 days. We retain the logs for this period of time in order to, among other things, analyze traffic to Whimsical’s website and investigate issues if something goes wrong on one of our websites.

## Security

While no online service is 100% secure, we work very hard to protect information about you against unauthorized access, use, alteration, or destruction, and take reasonable measures to do so, such as monitoring our Services for potential vulnerabilities and attacks.

## Choices

You have several choices available when it comes to information about you:

  * **Limit the Information that You Provide:** If you have an account with us, you can choose not to provide the optional account information, profile information, and transaction and billing information. Please keep in mind that if you do not provide this information, certain features of our Services may not be accessible.
  * **Opt-Out of Electronic Communications:** You may opt out of receiving promotional messages from us. Just follow the instructions in those messages. If you opt out of promotional messages, we may still send you other messages, like those about your account and legal notices.
  * **Set Your Browser to Reject Cookies:** At this time, Whimsical does not respond to “do not track” signals across all of our Services. However, you can usually choose to set your browser to remove or reject browser cookies before using Whimsical’s website, with the drawback that certain features of Whimsical’s website may not function properly without the aid of cookies.
  * **Delete Your Account:** While we’d be very sad to see you go, if you no longer want to use our Services, you can delete your whimsical.com account. Please keep in mind that we may continue to retain your information after closing your account, as described in How Long We Keep Information above–for example, when that information is reasonably needed to comply with (or demonstrate our compliance with) legal obligations such as law enforcement requests, or reasonably needed for our legitimate business interests.

## Your Rights

If you are located in certain countries, including Switzerland or those countries that fall under the scope of the European Union’s General Data Protection Regulation (AKA the “GDPR”), data protection laws give you rights with respect to your personal data, subject to any exemptions provided by the law, including the rights to:

  * Request access to your personal data;
  * Request correction or deletion of your personal data;
  * Object to our use and processing of your personal data;
  * Request that we limit our use and processing of your personal data; and
  * Request portability of your personal data.

You can usually access, correct, or delete your personal data using your account settings and tools that we offer, but if you aren’t able to do that, or you would like to contact us about one of the other rights, scroll down to How to Reach Us to, well, find out how to reach us. EU and Swiss individuals also have the right to make a complaint to a government supervisory authority.

## Controllers and Responsible Companies

Whimsical Inc. (WeWork, 2420 17th St, Denver, CO 80202, USA) is the controller for processing your personal information.

## How to Reach Us

If you have a question about this Privacy Policy, or you would like to contact us about any of the rights mentioned in the Your Rights section above, please [contact us](mailto:help@whimsical.com).

## Other Things You Should Know

### Data Processors

We rely on the following third-party services to help us run Whimsical smoothly:

  * [Amazon Web Services](https://aws.amazon.com/privacy/) (USA) - to host our infrastructure

  * [Sendgrid](https://sendgrid.com/policies/privacy/) (USA) - to send e-mails to customers

  * [Intercom](https://www.intercom.com/terms-and-policies#terms) (USA) - for customer support purposes

  * [Stripe](https://stripe.com/privacy-shield-policy) (USA) - to safely and securely handle customer billing.

### Transferring Information

Because Whimsical’s Services are offered worldwide, the information about you that we process when you use the Services in the EU or Switzerland may be used, stored, and/or accessed by individuals operating outside the European Economic Area (EEA) who work for us, or third party data processors. This is required for the purposes listed in the How and Why We Use Information section above. When providing information about you to entities outside the EEA, we will take appropriate measures to ensure that the recipient protects your personal information adequately in accordance with this Privacy Policy as required by applicable law. These measures include:

  * In the case of US based entities, entering into European Commission approved standard contractual arrangements with them, or ensuring they have signed up to the EU-US Privacy Shield; or
  * In the case of entities based in other countries outside the EEA, entering into European Commission approved standard contractual arrangements with them.

In connection with Whimsical’s processing of personal data it receives in the U.S. from the European Union or Switzerland (“EU Data”), Whimsical participates in, and complies with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework (collectively, the “Frameworks”) as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union and Switzerland to the United States. Whimsical has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles. Whimsical is committed to subjecting all EU Data, in reliance on the Frameworks, to the Frameworks’ applicable Principles. For purposes of enforcing compliance with the Frameworks, Whimsical is subject to the investigatory and enforcement authority of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission. If there is any conflict between the terms in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification, please visit <https://www.privacyshield.gov/>

Without limiting the above, Whimsical adheres to the Principle of Accountability for Onward Transfer. Whimsical shall remain liable under the Principles if its agent processes such personal information in a manner inconsistent with the Principles, unless Whimsical proves that it is not responsible for the event giving rise to the damage. As noted in Sharing Information above, we may transfer personal information (including EU Data) to our vendors, consultants and other service providers who need access to such EU Data to carry out work on our behalf. This personal data may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area (“EEA”) that may not be subject to equivalent data protection law.

In compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles, Whimsical commits to resolve complaints about our collection or use of your personal information. EU and Swiss individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding our Privacy Shield policy should first contact us at: [privacy@whimsical.com](mailto:privacy@whimsical.com)

Whimsical has further committed to cooperate with the panel established by the EU data protection authorities (DPAs) and the Swiss Federal Data Protection and Information Commissioner (FDPIC) with regard to unresolved Privacy Shield complaints concerning data transferred from the EU and Switzerland. Under certain conditions specified by the Principles and more fully described on the Privacy Shield website at <https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=How-to-Submit-a-Complaint>, you may also be able to invoke binding arbitration to resolve your complaint.

## Privacy Policy Changes

Although most changes are likely to be minor, Whimsical may change its Privacy Policy from time to time, and in Whimsical’s sole discretion. Whimsical encourages visitors to frequently check this page for any changes to its Privacy Policy. Your continued use of this site after any change in this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such change.
